R. EOGHAN HULBERT

(401) 203-5038 | Eoghan@Eoghy.dev | Woonsocket, RI 02895 - Relocating to Tacoma, WA

CAREER GOAL

Seeking long-term opportunities for technical development in information systems roles. The ideal roles would be associate level or above for Systems Analyst or Business Analyst; entry level for Automation Analyst or Systems Engineer. My 3-year goal is to gain new experience in enterprise systems and tools to meet qualifications for more in-depth technical roles.

EXPERIENCE

CSR II: CONSUMER DATA PROTECTION - MetLife

Dec 2019 to Present

- Provided website technical expertise and admin support for providers, benefits administrators and policyholders
- Elected as team ambassador for the MetLife Way leadership program to actively promote, train, and achieve organization goals and values within department
- Evaluated and participated in Root Cause Problem Solving initiative projects, providing resolutions and efficiencies for enhancing core operations, communication and workflow development
- Cross-trained in multiple departments, acted as resource and information liaison, and job coach to assist peers with complex problem solving, admin, and professional development
- Q1 2020 CSR Metrics Ranking: Top 50% of Global Customer Service, Top 25% of Web Support, Top 20% of Customer Data Protection

ASSOCIATE FINANCIAL SYSTEMS ANALYST - Amica Mutual Insurance

Sept 2018 to July 2019

- Provided technical expertise and mediation between accounting, external departments and vendor software distributors by building direct relationships with department managers and leads
- Analyzed development opportunities for current system enhancements and integrations to increase efficiency and promote task automations to meet business needs
- Managed mid to high-level accounting project portfolio from requirements gathering to delivery with an overall task success rate of 98% and minimal oversight
- Reduced wasted effort in Treasury by 58% annually with the development of custom automated systems to handle monthly bank reconciliation data for premium reimbursements

COLLECTIONS SERVICES REP I - Mapfre Insurance USA

May 2017 to July 2018

- Successfully managed \$35,000 collections portfolio with an average of 300 policies across multiple states and policy types, including high-risk accounts
- Proprietor of the national lines of business accounts in collections and trained new personnel in national policies and procedures as backup representatives
- Spearheaded multiple collections workflow analysis projects resulting in a 5% increase of premium recovery in national LOB from 2017 and reduction in third party commission payments by 30%
- Reduced wasted effort in initial policy research by 348 hours per person annually by implementing new collections criteria based on trends in repayment data analysis

R. EOGHAN HULBERT

(401) 203-5038 | Eoghan@Eoghy.dev | Woonsocket, RI 02895 - Relocating to Tacoma, WA

EXPERIENCE CONTINUED

SUPPORT SERVICES REP I - Mapfre Insurance USA

Nov 2015 to May 2017

- Identified, scanned and indexed an average of 900 incoming claims documents into business databases daily, exceeding 95% accuracy rate guidelines
- Collaborated in the Greater Place to Work Committee, hosted department events, and participated in continuing insurance education training with The Institutes
- Restructured document storage and destruction procedures reducing improper handling incidents to 0% and strengthened SEC and HIPAA regulatory compliance within backend operations

EDUCATION

SOUTHERN NEW HAMPSHIRE UNIVERSITY

B.A. Information Technology

Graduated: 12/2017

GPA: 3.25

Senior Project: Developed functional prototype web application based on a real-world business problem by drafting project management plans with given requirements and scope, adhering to project timelines, and utilizing multiple programming languages to produce deliverables

SKILLS

SOFT

Admin, Liability Insurance, Operations, Project Management, Requirements Gathering and Analysis, Root Cause Problem Solving, Time Management

TECHNICAL

Data Analysis, Database Management, Java, JavaScript, MS Server, Python, SQL, Systems Analysis and Design, Technical Writing, Usability Testing, VBA, Web App Development

COURSES

- Django 2 & Python | The Ultimate Web Development Bootcamp StackSkills.com
- 7 Habits of Highly Effective People Amica Insurance 2018
- Introduction to Property & Casualty Insurance The Institutes 2017

ADDITIONAL

LINKEDIN: LinkedIn.com/in/EHulbert

WEBSITE: Eoghy.dev